# **Curiculum Vitae 2024**

Corey J Scholes

2024-10-10

Scientist and Analysis Executive with 15 years of experience bridging the gap between clinical research and evidence-generation with routine practice across diverse settings. A collaborative leader with the ability to communicate technically across multidisciplinary teams and influence behaviour change to embed data-driven practices into long-term strategies. An experienced consultant assisting executive teams to bring about change within their own organisations through strategic planning, ideation and implementation of complex systems.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Co-Founder and Director

## EBM Analytics Jul 2016 - Present

- Spearheaded the growth of EBM Analytics from a startup to a successful company with annual revenues exceeding \$750,000.
- Built a strong client base across public and private health sectors, government, and industry, located in nearly every state in Australia.
- Expanded the team from 1 to up to 10 full-time equivalent positions, fostering a culture of collaboration and innovation.
- Designed, implemented, and supported complex specialist clinical registries for sports medicine, joint arthroplasty and oncology, resulting in improved patient outcomes reporting and insights.
- Established routine reporting of outcomes for clinical, health management, and industry audiences, providing valuable insights for stakeholders.
- Provided boutique data and research consultancy, with output including (but not limited to) peer-reviewed research articles and high-level reports.

#### Chief Science Officer

### EBM Analytics 2020 - Present

- Provide scientific leadership to clinical research projects and engagements in which the company is involved.
- Represent the company's interests in the establishment of strategic partnerships and collaborations.
- Develop and implement research strategy for clientele.
- Offer guidance on methodological approaches to ensure high-quality research outputs.
- Collaborate with clients, clinicians, researchers, and other stakeholders to understand stakeholder requirements, provide scientific guidance, and communicate project results effectively.
- Develop and maintain a deep understanding of various research methodologies, including clinical trials, observational studies, health outcomes, health services and systematic review/meta-analysis research.
- Lead the analysis and interpretation of complex data sets, including clinical registry data, providing actionable insights to clients and stakeholders while ensuring regulatory compliance with relevant guidelines and industry standards.
- Oversee engineers, analysts, and clinicians, providing guidance internally and externally to the company on project management, data analysis, and output preparation.

#### Director of Research

#### Sydney Orthopaedic Research Institute 2009 - 2016

- Plan, lead and manage research activities within the Institute.
- Develop research strategy in consultation with Institute Directors.
- Conduct regular reporting to the Board on research, project and operational activities of the Institute.
- Contribute to financial planning, monitoring and reporting.
- Offer guidance on methodological approaches to ensure high-quality research outputs.
- Provide close assistance to clinician researchers in the preparation of presentations and research articles.
- Act as primary point of contact for staffing, contracting and supplier engagements.
- Champion transition of IT infrastructure to updated and upgraded software and hardware to support growing operational load.

### **Army Officer**

Australian Army Reserve 2009 - 2015

- Responsible for the training, administration and leadership of up to 50 personnel
- Provide command presence and tactical leadership during simulated and live-fire infantry training exercises and ceremonial activities.
- Train, mentor and develop team leaders under command, including the planning and conduct of training activities specific to their development.
- Directly contribute to soldier training through presentation and demonstration in classroom and field environments.
- Coordinate enabling elements to support training activities and simulated combat operations.
- Contribute to command activities in collaboration with Senior Management within joint planning, budgeting and personnel administration.
- Contribute to operational planning, including risk management, for training activities for up to 200 personnel.

## **Teaching Assistant**

Queensland University of Technology 2006 - 2008

- Plan, prepare and deliver lectures on fundamental and advanced biomechanics and functional anatomy.
- Conduct syllabus planning and preparation for semester units and the fundamental and advanced levels.
- Conduct tutorial sessions to develop student practical skills in movement analysis and exercise prescription.

#### Research Assistant

Queensland University of Technology 2004 - 2005

- Assist with research projects on worker health in the coal mining industry.
- Prepare research output materials for presentations and government reports on the stateof-the-art in worker health within the industry
- Contribute to on-site measurements of contractors in active coal mines within the Central Highlands of Queensland.

### **EDUCATION**

Doctor of Philosophy – Exercise Science Queensland University of Technology Feb 2005 – Oct 2010

• The effects of fatigue on knee function during landing

- Vice-Chancellor Scholarship (2005-2008)
- Supervisors
  - Dr Michael D McDonald
  - Prof Anthony W Parker

BApp Sci (Hons) Queensland University of Technology 2004

BApp Sci (Human Movement Studies) Queensland University of Technology 2001 - 2003

## CREDENTIALS

- Good Clinical Practice
- Working With Children Check

## **MEMBERSHIPS**

- International Society for Arthroscopy and Knee Orthopaedic Surgery
- Australian Institute of Company Directors
- Australia and New Zealand Orthopaedic Research Society (Past)

## **SKILLS**

## **Technical**

- Statistics and Methods
  - Extract, transform and load data processing
  - Modelling (Prediction and Inference)
  - Machine Learning
  - Natural language processing
  - Signal processing
  - Time series analysis
  - Survival analysis
  - Multistate modelling
  - Meta-analysis and regression
  - Clinical trials
  - Clinical quality registry
- Languages and Environments (familiarity and working knowledge)

- R, RStudio, Quarto
- Stata
- Matlab
- Google Cloud Platform
  - \* LookerStudio
  - \* App Scripts
- SQL
- Regular expressions
- Version control (git)
- Project management (ClickUp)

### Non-Technical

- Leadership, business development, ethics, governance
- Collaboration, communication, public-speaking, team-building
- Problem-solving, adaptability, self-awareness, conflict resolution
- Strategic thinking, risk assessment and mitigation, long-term planning

## **SCIENTIFIC OUTPUT**

A summary of my research output is available at Google Scholar and Orcid.org. My summary profile from Publons (Web of Science) also illustrates my contributions to peer-review with respected journals within my field. Selected citations to illustrate my experience in key science domains are summarised below, including preprint articles that have yet to be submitted for peer review.

Domain	Summary	Example Citations
Meta-science	Systematic Review	(Corey Scholes et al. 2015)
	Meta-Analysis	(Harrison-Brown et al. 2019)
	Meta-Regression	(Corey Scholes, Ektas, et al. 2023)
Open Science	Trial registration	(Ektas et al. 2019; Fatima et al. 2022)
	Protocol development	
Computed Assisted	Shoulder, Hip, Knee	(Nashikkar, Scholes, and Haber 2019;
Surgery		Lustig et al. 2013; Corey Scholes,
		Schwagli, and Ireland 2023; Oussedik et
		al. 2012)
Clinical Quality	Description and validation	(Jenio et al. 2019; Corey Scholes, Eng,
Registry	of registries in practice	et al. 2023; Lee et al. 2020)

Domain	Summary	Example Citations
Clinical Outcomes	Description and analysis of	(Harrison-Brown et al. 2024; Corey
and Prediction	observational data in	Scholes, Fatima, et al. 2024)
Modelling	practice	
Clinical Trials	Conduct and reporting of clinical trials	(De Wall et al. 2011)
Population Health	Use of national level resources to answer clinical questions	(CJ Scholes et al. 2019; Corey Scholes, Holder, et al. 2024)
Health Services	Assessment and implementation of model of care changes	(Barton et al. 2024; Tuckerman et al. 2020)

## REFERENCES

- Barton, Loren, Mark Nelson, Corey Scholes, and Kirsten Strudwick. 2024. "A Physiotherapy-Led Review of Guideline-Based Care for Community-Dwelling Older People Presenting to a Metropolitan Hospital with Accidental Falls." *Australasian Journal on Ageing* 43 (1): 43–51.
- De Wall, Mathew, Corey J Scholes, Sandeep Patel, Myles RJ Coolican, and David A Parker. 2011. "Tibial Fixation in Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Prospective Randomized Study Comparing Metal Interference Screw and Staples with a Centrally Placed Polyethylene Screw and Sheath." *The American Journal of Sports Medicine* 39 (9): 1858–64.
- Ektas, Nalan, Corey Scholes, Selin Kulaga, Garry Kirwan, Binglong Lee, and Christopher Bell. 2019. "Recovery of Knee Extension and Incidence of Extension Deficits Following Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury and Treatment: A Systematic Review Protocol." *Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery and Research* 14: 1–7.
- Fatima, Manaal, Nalan Ektas, Corey Scholes, Michael Symes, and Andrew Wines. 2022. "The Effect of Osteotomy Technique (Flat-Cut Vs Wedge-Cut Weil) on Pain Relief and Complication Incidence Following Surgical Treatment for Metatarsalgia in a Private Metropolitan Clinic: Protocol for a Randomised Controlled Trial." Trials 23 (1): 690.
- Harrison-Brown, Meredith, Corey Scholes, Milad Ebrahimi, Christopher Bell, and Garry Kirwan. 2024. "Applying Models of Care for Total Hip and Knee Arthroplasty: External Validation of a Published Predictive Model to Identify Extended Stay Risk Prior to Lower-Limb Arthroplasty." Clinical Rehabilitation 38 (5): 700–712.
- Harrison-Brown, Meredith, Corey Scholes, Kholoud Hafsi, Maimuna Marenah, Jinjie Li, Fadi Hassan, Nicola Maffulli, and William D Murrell. 2019. "Efficacy and Safety of Culture-Expanded, Mesenchymal Stem/Stromal Cells for the Treatment of Knee Osteoarthritis: A Systematic Review Protocol." Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery and Research 14: 1–7.

- Jenio, Frank Zackary, Corey Scholes, Maimuna Marenah, Jinjie Li, Mac Cowley, Milad Ebrahimi, Meredith Harrison-Brown, and William D Murrell. 2019. "Quality in Practice: Implementation of a Clinical Outcomes Registry in Regenerative Medicine." *Annals of Translational Medicine* 7 (7).
- Lee, Binglong, Milad Ebrahimi, Nalan Ektas, Chee Han Ting, MacDougal Cowley, Corey Scholes, and Christopher Bell. 2020. "Implementation and Quality Assessment of a Clinical Orthopaedic Registry in a Public Hospital Department." *BMC Health Services Research* 20: 1–9.
- Lustig, Sébastien, Corey J Scholes, Sam I Oussedik, Vera Kinzel, Myles RJ Coolican, and David A Parker. 2013. "Unsatisfactory Accuracy as Determined by Computer Navigation of VISIONAIRE Patient-Specific Instrumentation for Total Knee Arthroplasty." *The Journal of Arthroplasty* 28 (3): 469–73.
- Nashikkar, Piyush S, Corey J Scholes, and Mark D Haber. 2019. "Computer Navigation Re-Creates Planned Glenoid Placement and Reduces Correction Variability in Total Shoulder Arthroplasty: An in Vivo Case-Control Study." *Journal of Shoulder and Elbow Surgery* 28 (12): e398–409.
- Oussedik, Sam, Corey Scholes, Duncan Ferguson, Justin Roe, and David Parker. 2012. "Is Femoral Component Rotation in a TKA Reliably Guided by the Functional Flexion Axis?" Clinical Orthopaedics and Related Research® 470 (11): 3227–32.
- Scholes, CJ, M Ebrahimi, SB Farah, C Field, R Cordingley, D Kerr, and L Kohan. 2019. "The Outcome and Survival of Metal-on-Metal Hip Resurfacing in Patients Aged Less Than 50 Years: A Prospective Observational Cohort Study with Minimum Ten-Year Follow-up." The Bone & Joint Journal 101 (1): 113–20.
- Scholes, Corey, Nalan Ektas, Meredith Harrison-Brown, Maha Jegatheesan, Ashwin Rajesh, Garry Kirwan, and Christopher Bell. 2023. "Persistent Knee Extension Deficits Are Common After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomised Controlled Trials." Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy 31 (8): 3172–85.
- Scholes, Corey, Kevin Eng, Meredith Harrison-Brown, Milad Ebrahimi, Graeme Brown, Stephen Gill, and Richard Page. 2023. "Patient Registry of Upper Limb Outcomes (PRULO): A Protocol for an Orthopaedic Clinical Quality Registry to Monitor Treatment Outcomes." Journal of Surgical Protocols and Research Methodologies 2023 (4): snad014.
- Scholes, Corey, Manaal Fatima, Cooper Moody, Kevin Eng, and Richard S Page. 2024. "Stage 2a IDEAL Evaluation of a Third-Generation Biocomposite Suture Anchor in Arthroscopic Rotator Cuff Repair: Subgroup Cohort Analysis of the PRULO Registry with 12-Month Follow Up." medRxiv, 2024–06.
- Scholes, Corey, Carl Holder, Christopher Vertullo, and Matthew Lawrence Broadhead. 2024. "Stay or Go? Outcomes of Lower Limb Arthroplasty in Patients Travelling Away from Home for Surgery: A Cross-Sectional Analysis of the AOANJRR Comparing Patient Residence and Hospital Remoteness." medRxiv, 2024–08.
- Scholes, Corey, Eleanor R Houghton, Matthew Lee, and Sebastien Lustig. 2015. "Meniscal Translation During Knee Flexion: What Do We Really Know?" *Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy* 23 (1): 32–40.

Scholes, Corey, Tobias Schwagli, and John Ireland. 2023. "CT Validation of Intraoperative Imageless Navigation (Naviswiss) for Component Positioning Accuracy in Primary Total Hip Arthroplasty in Supine Patient Position: A Prospective Observational Cohort Study in a Single-Surgeon Practice." Arthroplasty 5 (1): 63.

Tuckerman, Kirby, Wendy Potts, Milad Ebrahimi, Corey Scholes, and Mark Nelson. 2020. "Evolution of Service Metrics and Utilisation of Objective Discharge Criteria in Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Rehabilitation: A Retrospective Cohort Study with Historical Control in a Public Hospital Physiotherapy Department." *Archives of Physiotherapy* 10: 1–11.